ANISHA HIRANI

anisha.hirani11@gmail.com Tel: 07562314978 GitHub CV

PERSONAL PROFILE:

A recent graduate from Maker's Academy, pursuing a career in software engineering with a past experience of tutoring in the education sector. I was inspired by seeing how vital technology was within the current education system which pushed me further to take up code and stem a career out of it.

I'm heavily involved with a non-profit organisation called HSS (UK) for the past 14 years which instils the ethos of hard work, good morals, selfless working and aligns with my passion for tech for good. I pride myself in managing my time, having managed my studies, personal life and professional development successfully up until now.

PROJECTS:

ReelPlaces	Built a web-app in a team so users see filming locations in their chosen location, with a map.	Tech Stack: React Native, Jest, MongoDB, Express, Node.
Acebook	Built a web-app in a team, similar to Facebook - make posts,comment, like etc.	Tech Stack: MERN Stack, Jest, Cypress, Mongoose, Handlebars.
<u>MakersBnB</u>	A web-app similar to AirBnB that allows you to rent a space, make bookings etc.	Tech Stack: Ruby, PostgreSQL, Sinatra, RSpec.
<u>Portfolio</u>	Solo project showing things I have worked on.	Tech Stack: Javascript, HTML, Tailwind CSS, Next.js Vercel

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE:

Makers Academy - 16-week Software Development bootcamp

(Oct 2022 - Feb 2023)

- Focussed on key languages like; Ruby, Javascript, SQL, HTML & CSS, Sinatra along with testing.
- Daily pair programmed with multiple individuals, as well as focussed on self learning and improvement.
- Concentrated on Object-Oriented Programming and Test Driven Development.
- Balanced time between being patient with producing code when working alongside my peers.
- Debugged and refactored my code as well as pre-written code for better learning and understanding.
- Used my curiosity and initiative to learn about Github as for version control.
- Participated on team projects that used API's and worked on features that involved Google Maps and IMDb.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Hindu Swayamsevak Sangh (HSS UK)

(Jan 2009 - Present)

Volunteer

A not-for-profit organisation focusing on character development by instilling values based on the Hindu culture and developing life skills.

- Organise and lead activities to promote development, service to humanity and unity through Hindu values.
- Supporting all ages and developing them through regular weekly activities consisting of games, yoga, health & fitness, educational and culture from ages 5 to 70 + years.
- Attention to detail required when leading monthly meetings, working under pressure to meet deadlines and obtaining feedback to keep the sessions running effectively.
- Communication and self organisation was vital to ensure everybody was receiving the same development opportunities.
- Worked in a team to successfully manage and oversee a public yoga session with the local temple and community for International Yoga Day.
- Leading and collaborating frequently with new people to orchestrate charitable events and do selfless work.

Explore Learning

(Feb 2021 - Dec 2022)

Maths & English Tutor

- Responsible for delivering and planning high quality lessons on a regular basis to over 100 students.
- Adapting to children's different learning abilities, as well as being able to empathise with them.
- Communicating with parents to provide relevant feedback on their child.
- Having patience when explaining tough concepts to the class.

EDUCATION:

Plumstead Manor Sixth Form

(Sept 2020 - Jul 2022)

12 GCSEs including Gujarati.

INTERESTS:

- Travelling
- Music playing piano & singing
- Various sports & going to the gym
- Volunteering